For the sake of saving the kingdom,
Elizabeth continued her search for the Sins.
(ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)＜王国を救うため
残る七つの大罪を捜すｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽは➡
オーダンの村で
不思議な少年に出会った＞
She encountered a mysterious man in the village of Ordan.
＜ 一方
メリオダスたちは 七つの大罪➡
Meanwhile, Meliodas and the others stumble upon a battle between the Armor Giant,
色欲の罪 ゴウセルと思しき
鎧の巨人が➡
believed to be the Goat's Sin, Gowther, and the murderous group Dawn Roar.
殺戮集団｢暁闇の咆哮｣に
襲撃されている現場に➡
駆けつける｡ しかし…＞
However!
(ﾒﾘｵﾀﾞｽ)ゴウセル！
Gowther!
＜彼こそが 五人目の大罪人｡
その名は…＞
He was the fifth member of the Sins.
His name is...
Member of the Seven Deadly Sins,
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)
七つの大罪が一人 色欲の罪➡
the Goat's Sin of Lust, Gowther.
色欲の罪 ゴウセル｡
This kid is a member of the legendary Seven?
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)
この若造が 七つの大罪ですって？
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)信じられない…｡
(ﾜｲﾝﾊｲﾄ)いや➡
Impossible!
No, this guy was able to stop my fully charged arrow with his bare hands.
こいつは 俺のフルチャージの矢を
素手で止めた｡
そんな芸当が
ただの あんちゃんにできるとは➡
An ordinary boy wouldn't be able to do such a thing.
考えられねぇっす｡
(ｼﾞﾘｱﾝ)んん…｡
Correct.
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)そのとおり｡ 正真正銘
俺は色欲の罪 ゴウセルだ｡
I am indeed Gowther, the Goat's Sin.
＜ これは いまだ
人と 人ならざるものの世界が➡
This is a tale of humans and beings from other worlds.
分かたれてはいなかった
古の物語＞
It is a story of ancient times.
＜聖騎士を有する国は
リオネス一国にとどまらず➡
Liones wasn't the only nation with the power of the Holy Knights.
ブリタニア全土に及んだ＞
They are used throughout all Britannia.
＜魔力は力であり その力こそが➡
Magic is power.
And that very power
一国の命運をも左右した＞
is what shapes the fate of each nation.
Amongst the numerous Holy Knights,
＜数ある騎士たちの中で
ブリタニア全土に➡
there is one group whose fame stretched all across Britannia.
その名を轟かせた
その者たちの名は…＞
And that group's name was—
're
Those who wander looking for answers, those who question in confusion
samayoi tou mono mo tomadoi kou mono mo
Will go beyond all sin.
subete no tsumi wo koe
Episode 15
Unholy Knight
(ﾊﾞﾝ)へえ～ 鎧の中身は➡
Oh, so this is what was inside the armor all along.
こうなってたのかよ｡
俺は てっきり➡
I totally figured you were
a big old geezer or something.
でっかいおやじが
入ってるのかと思ってたぜ｡
Judging by your posture, stride, tone of voice, attitude, and the scar on your face,
姿勢 歩き方 声音 態度 頬の傷➡
お前は やはり 不死身のバンか｡
you are, without a doubt, The Undead Ban.
うわっ！ その感じ ゴウセルだわ｡
Whoa, this vibe! And you're definitely Gowther.
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)ん…｡
あいつも 七つの大罪？
He's one of the Sins too?
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)ということは あの限りなく
俺の知るメリオダスと➡
That must mean this young boy over here
who looks exactly like the Meliodas I knew is...
瓜二つの少年は…｡
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)ん？
そうです
俺が 団長メリオダスです！
Yeah. I'm the captain, Meliodas!
このチンチクリンが
七つの大罪の団長だと!?
This shorty is the Captain
of the Seven Deadly Sins?!
えっ ショック？
Eh? Is that a shock?
What a surprise.
驚いたな｡
そういう顔には見えねぇぞ｡
Your face doesn't exactly look surprised.
なら あれはどうだ？
絶対 驚く！ キングだぜ｡
Well, how about that?
This'll be surprising. That's King!
No, he's not the same person.
いや 別人だ｡ 骨 声音 体臭が➡
His skeletal structure, voice,
and body odor are nothing like King's.
キングとは まるで別物だろう｡
体臭？
Body odor?
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)ふん！
キモっ！
Gross—
That's definitely him.
間違いなく本人だ｡
切り替え 早っ！
Changed your mind pretty quick!
パン パン
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)ワンダフォ～！➡
Wonderful!
ゴウセルに続いて 七つの大罪の
三人に出会えるなんて➡
Meeting three other Sins in addition to Gowther...
ハッピー！ ぜひ一度➡
Happy!
I'd enjoy nothing more than to
fight you all, but unfortunately,
手合わせ願いたいところだけど…
残念｡➡
今日のアタシたちの任務は➡
our mission for today is just to bring back the head of the Armor Giant.
あくまで あの鎧巨人の首を
持ち帰ることなのよん｡
鎧に入ってんのは 誰なんだ？
よく分からない｡
Who's inside your armor right now?
I'm not exactly sure.
ん？
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)さあ➡
Now, time for us to get back to work.
仕事の時間よ｡
彼を そっとしておいてくれないか｡
頼む｡
Is there any chance you could leave him alone?
Please.
Hey, Gowther. Why can't you
just let them fight this monster?
(ﾊﾞﾝ)おい ゴウセル
勝手にやらせときゃいいだろ｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)まあ 確かに おいらたちも
ゴウセルだと思ったから➡
Well, yeah...
We were only protecting it because we thought it was you, Gowther.
守ろうとしただけだし… ねえ？
う～ん｡
(鎧巨人)ぼおぉ～～‼
この魔力を肌で感じたうえで
まだ 彼を倒せると？
After experiencing his power,
do you still think you can defeat him?
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)倒せる｡
無論 アタシたちのうち 二人…➡
We can.
No doubt, two of us—
いや 一人は確実に死ぬ｡➡
No, one of us will die.
だが 確実に
こいつの首を討ち取れるわ｡
But I also have no doubt that
we will be able to take its head.
冷静な判断だ｡
ならば やむをえん｡
A calm, objective assessment.
Then I have no choice.
ザシュ！
持っていけ｡
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)なんの… つもり？
Take it.
What are you planning?
いちばんの平和的解決法だ｡
This is the most peaceful solution.
俺たち三つ巴の戦いが起これば
その余波で➡
If we were to start a three-way battle here,
the village of Ordan at the foot of the mountain would end up destroyed in the crossfire.
麓のオーダンの
村人の全滅は必至｡➡
それに 死んだ騎士たちも
これで多少は報われよう｡
And with this, we can also pay our
respects to the knights who fell here.
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)ふっ｡ それじゃあ 頂くわ｡
Well then, we'll take it.
Are you sure, Threader?
いいのか スレイダー!?
僕らの獲物を 勝手に…｡
He just took our target and—
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)童は お黙り！
あっ｡
Silence, child!
I like you, Goat's Sin, Gowther.
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)気に入ったわ
色欲の罪 ゴウセル｡➡
その強さと伝説に敬意を表して
退いてあげる｡➡
I'll respect your strength and the
legends of the Sins and retreat for now.
でも もし いずれ あなたたちの
首を取れと 命令が出れば➡
But if we were to receive an order for your heads someday, then...
そのときは…｡ まあいいわ｡➡
When that time comes...
Well, you understand.
バイバ～イ｡
Bye-bye!
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)バイバ～イ｡
(３人)ん？
Bye-bye.
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)でも 驚いたな｡
君は このモンスターに➡
That was a surprise.
It seemed like you were
sympathizing with this monster.
同情しているように見えたのに｡
Sympathy...
同情…｡ 俺は 同情しているのか？
Was I sympathizing?
(ｷﾝｸﾞ ﾊﾞﾝ)ん？
これ お前の鎧だよな｡
身代わりにでもしてたのか？
Isn't this your armor?
Did you use him as a scapegoat?
No, though it did end up that way.
いいや｡
しかし 結果的に そうなった｡
彼を 俺だと勘違いしたのだろう｡
They probably mistook him for me.
That's because they've never seen your real face.
(ﾊﾞﾝ)お前の素顔なんか
見たことねぇし｡
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)そうか｡ ということは
変装は不要だったのか｡
I see.
That means a disguise was unnecessary after all.
それにしても
こんなモンスター 初めて見るな｡
Either way, I've never seen a monster like this before.
彼の魔力の奥底から
かすかに漂うにおい…➡
The faint smell that emanates from the core of his power.
おそらく 元は人間だ｡
えっ？
It was most likely a human.
んん…｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)人間!?
Human?!
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)さて
頑張って 四人で食い止めよう｡
Well then, the four of us
should do our best to stop him.
あらら｡ どうなってんの？
What's going on?
Didn't I say already? If this devolved into a three-way battle, chaos would've ensued.
言ったろ？ 三つ巴でぶつかれば
事態は 混乱を極めた｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)
く… 首をはねたのに生きてる！
I-It's still alive after being decapitated!
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)ああ｡
首は もはや飾りにすぎない｡
Well, the head is nothing more than a decoration.
それの どこが元人間なの!?
異常すぎるよ！
And how could this thing have been a human?!
This is absurd!
もちろん ただの人間ではない｡➡
Of course, it wasn't just any ordinary human being.
聖騎士のなれの果てだ｡
It's the remnant of a former Holy Knight.
(鎧巨人)ぐおぉ～～‼
I don't understand.
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)しかし 解せないな｡➡
ゴウセルは どんな理由で化け物に
鎧を着せていたっていうんだ？
Why would Gowther make
a monster wear his own armor?
(ｼﾞﾘｱﾝ)興味ないわね｡ 私は もっと
ヤツらと戦ってみたかった｡
I couldn't care less.
I just wish we had gotten to fight them.
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)解せないわ｡
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)だろ？
I don't understand...
Right?
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)なぜ
ヘルブラムのじじいは こいつを➡
Why was that geezer Helbram so
determined to kill this strange monster?
執拗に殺したがっていたのか｡
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)あっ｡
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)なぜ 手飼いの新世代を
使わなかったのか｡
And why didn't he use his favorite pawns, the New Generation?
(ﾜｲﾝﾊｲﾄ)新世代の手には
負えない案件だったからっすよ｡
Maybe the New Generation
wouldn't have been able to handle it.
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)
アタシには この化け物の存在を➡
It seems to me like he's desperately trying to hide the existence of this monster.
必死になって
隠ぺいしているように感じるわ｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)聖騎士のなれの果て？
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)感じるはずだ｡➡
The remnant of a former Holy Knight?
Can't you feel it?
邪悪な魔力の奔流の底に漂う➡
A Holy Knight's power is buried deep underneath, within that evil magic.
よどんだ聖騎士の魔力を｡➡
Therefore, I forced it into my armor to seal that malevolent force.
その邪悪で大きな魔力を
抑えるために➡
俺の鎧を着せていたが
度重なる破損で➡
However, it looks like the seal has
been broken due to frequent damage.
封印が解かれてしまった｡
そういうことか｡
So that's how it is.
少なくとも 話の通じる
相手じゃなさそうだな｡
Anyway, it doesn't look like
something that can be reasoned with.
ぐおぉ～～！
ドーン！
Let's send him flying!
飛ばすぞ！
おう！
Yeah!
ドカッ ドカッ ドカッ ドカッ…
ぐおぉ～！
あだっ！
ふっふっふ～！ 二人とも➡
You two, a battle should always begin with
the observation of how the opponent reacts.
戦いにおいては
まず 相手の出方を見るべきだよ｡
(ﾊﾞﾝ)えっらそうに！
おお～ もふもふ！
Quit bein' so cocky!
So fluffy!
Spirit Spear Chastiefol, Form Two, Guardian.
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)霊槍シャスティフォル
第二形態 ｢守護獣｣｡➡
神樹は 外敵から身を守るため➡
To protect itself,
自らに生える苔に形を与え
戦わせるんだ｡➡
the Sacred Tree shapeshifts
the moss that grows upon it.
苔から作られた体は
あらゆる攻撃をいなし➡
The body made from moss
can parry any physical attack,
水分を多く含む体は
炎に強い耐性を持つ｡
and because it contains a high concentration of water, it's highly resistant to fire.
ぐわぁ～！
Frozen Breath
ぐおっ！
バキン！
寒さには弱かった｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)ノー！
But it's weak to cold!
ゴウセル 次は お前だ！
You're up next, Gowther!
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)眼鏡が曇った｡➡
My glasses have fogged up.
しばらく 三人で もたせてくれ｡
(３人)えっ？
You three can hold it off on your own for a bit.
(鎧巨人)ぐおぉ～～！
ドーン！
ぐおぉ～！
(ﾊﾞﾝ)ふぅ～ やれやれ｡
Well, well...
Cap'n, this is gonna be tough with our bare hands.
団ちょ 素手じゃ きついかもな｡
えり好みしている場合じゃねぇよな｡
Guess this isn't the time to be picky.
I'm borrowing this!
借りるぜ｡
ぶわぁ～！
Despair Venom
普通の武器が通用するのか？
Would an ordinary weapon even have any effect?
Enchant: Hellblaze
Enchant: Hellblaze!
付呪･｢獄炎｣！
ぐおぉ～～…｡
Black flames?
黒い炎!?
あれは…｡
That's...
団ちょ！ 一気に畳みかけろ！
おう！
Cap'n!
End it in one strike!
Yeah!
ない… く… れ…｡
はっ！
Don't... me... please...
早く とどめを刺せ！
(鎧巨人)ぐおぉ！
Hurry up and end it!
あっ やべっ｡
バカが！
Ah, crap.
You idiot!
ドスッ！
光の矢!? この隙に団長を！
An arrow of light?
Now's your chance!
What're you doing, Cap'n?
何やってる 団ちょ!?
今のは いけたろうが！
You could've finished it!
あいつ 何か話した｡
あっ｡
He said something.
おそらく 元の聖騎士だ｡
He must be the original Holy Knight!
So what? Hurry up and kill it!
それがなんだ!? さっさと殺せ！
まだ生きてるんだぞ！
He's still alive!
何 甘えたこと言ってやがる！
くっ！
Quit being so naive!
Are you quarreling amongst yourselves?
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)喧嘩しているのか？
Gowther...
ゴウセル…｡ ん？➡
動きが止まった？ 倒したのか？
It stopped moving?
Did we defeat it?
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)
いいや 幻にとらわれたのだ｡➡
No, he is merely caught in an illusion.
That is the power of my Invasion.
それが俺の魔力 ｢侵食｣｡➡
Invasion
He is currently enveloped in the scene
from his past that he most desired to see.
彼は今 自身が最も戻りたかった
遠き日の幻の中にいる｡
As ever, you're a sly and painstaking bastard.
相変わらず
陰険で まどろっこしい野郎だ｡
さっさと殺しゃあいい｡
Just hurry up and kill him.
俺には 彼を殺せない｡
あん？
I cannot do that.
Huh?
He never asked to be born like this.
彼は
自ら望んで生まれた存在ではない｡
Therefore, I cannot kill him.
だから 俺には殺せない｡
けっ！ この世に 好きで生まれる
人間がいるかっつぅの｡
As if anyone asked to be born into this world.
Step aside. I'll kill it.
どけ 俺が殺す｡
Stop.
やめろ｡ あいつには
まだ人間の部分が残ってる｡
He's still partly human.
(ﾃﾞｨｱﾝﾇ)団長 遅いねぇ｡
Captain sure is late.
Maybe he caught something amazing?
(ﾎｰｸ)すっげぇ獲物
捕まえてんのかもな｡
Lord Meliodas...
(ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)メリオダス様…｡
≫ドンドン(ﾉｯｸ)
≫お～い すまんが開いとるか？
あっ｡
Hello? Excuse me, are you open?
All the other places are closed.
なんじゃ ほかは
どこも閉まってるようでな｡
いらっしゃいませ｡ あっ➡
Welcome!
Is that you, Mr. Cain?
ケインさん… でしたっけ？
確か バイゼルで
メリオダス様と戦った…｡
If I remember correctly, you fought Lord Meliodas back at Byzel.
(ｹｲﾝ)そんな…｡ これは夢か？➡
Impossible...
This must be a dream.
Liz!
リズ！
えっ？
If they're quarreling amongst themselves, does that mean they get along well?
喧嘩をするということは
仲がいいのか？
That's not really quarreling.
喧嘩ってわけじゃ…｡
仲よきことは➡
Is friendship... a beautiful thing?
美しきこと… なのか？
はい？
What?
(ﾊﾞﾝ)ふっ｡ 俺に命令すんな｡
Don't order me around.
I see, so Meliodas is fine.
(ｹｲﾝ)そうか メリオダスは無事か｡
うんうん よかった｡
どうぞ｡
That's great to hear.
Here.
My apologies for having the
Princess of Liones wait on me.
すまんのう リオネスの王女様に｡
いえ｡
It's fine.
However, I am surprised.
それにしても驚いたわい｡➡
端正な顔だち
柔らかな声も よう似ておる｡➡
Your beautiful face and
gentle voice are just like hers.
リズが生き返ったかと
思ってしもうた｡➡
I thought maybe Liz had come back to life.
If that girl were still alive, she would've been a beautiful woman by now.
あの娘が生きとれば もう
妙齢の女性になっとるはずじゃ｡
ケインさんの娘さんですか？
Was she your daughter, Mr. Cain?
(ｹｲﾝ)｢リズ｣は愛称でな｡
名前は 王女様と同じ➡
Liz was her nickname.
Her real name was Elizabeth, just like you, Princess.
エリザベス｡
えっ？
She was Meliodas's lover.
(ｹｲﾝ)メリオダスの恋人じゃった｡
あっ…｡
Liz was originally a knight of an enemy kingdom.
リズは 敵国の女騎士でな｡➡
ダナフォールへの夜襲で
失敗し捕らえられ➡
She was captured after a failed night raid on Danafor.
処刑宣告された｡
それを救ったのは ほかでもない➡
She was sentenced to death.
And the one who saved her was none other than
the captain of the Danafor Holy Knights, Meliodas.
当時 ダナフォールの
聖騎士団長だったメリオダスじゃ｡➡
当然 ほかの者は
口をそろえ異議を唱えた｡
Obviously, he was met with strong objection, but...
So I guess that makes you all my enemies.
(回想)((そんじゃ
お前ら全員 俺の敵な))
(ﾘｽﾞ)((甘っちょろい男だな))
You're just a stupid boy!
Really?
What do you mean, "really?"
I bet you're just after my body.
((どうせ
お前の目的は 私の体なんだろ!?))
If you come near me, I'll kill you!
((近寄ったら ぶち殺す！))
((まあ まあ そう興奮すんなよ))
Come now, don't get so excited.
((飯でも食おうぜ))
((この！))
Let's eat.
You—!
Originally, Liz was sold to the opposing kingdom as a slave.
(ｹｲﾝ)リズは もともと その敵国に
奴隷として売られた身でな｡➡
自分以外の誰のことも
信用していなかった｡➡
She never trusted anyone, aside from herself.
じゃが これも
運命の出会いというやつかのう｡➡
Perhaps you could call it a fated meeting...
甘っちょろい男と反発しながらも➡
Even though she always clashed with that simple boy,
she gradually found herself drawn to him.
リズは 次第に
メリオダスに惹かれていった｡➡
リズ自身も
不思議な魅力を持つ娘でな｡➡
Liz always had this charming aura about her as well.
わしらも
リズに 心を開いていった｡➡
And so we began to open up to her.
These were all scenes from long ago.
全ては 遠い日の風景じゃ｡
甘っちょろい男だなんて…｡
A simple boy...
メリオダス様は とても…
とても優しいだけです｡
Lord Meliodas is just really kind, that's all.
ふふっ｡ メリオダスが➡
Do you know why Meliodas never wields a real sword?
まともな剣を持たん理由を
知っておるか？
He's too strong.
(ｹｲﾝ)強すぎるんじゃよ｡
ヤツと 本気で剣を交えて➡
No one who's fought him seriously using swords has ever come out unscathed.
無事じゃった者はおらん｡
だから 剣を持たん｡
That's why he won't use one.
Well, at the same time,
he's too kind for his own good.
そう…
同時にヤツは 優しすぎるんじゃ｡
それは？
リズが➡
What's that?
It was a gift for Meliodas from Liz.
かつて
メリオダスに贈ったものじゃ｡
I don't need a sword.
((剣は不要だ｡
俺は 誰も殺したくねぇ))
I don't want to kill anyone.
So I've been holding onto it all this time.
(ｹｲﾝ)それで わしが代わりに
ずっと預かっておるんじゃよ｡
Ban, why did you kill him?
バン… なんで殺した？
I just ended that bastard's miserable, shitty life as a monster.
化け物になっちまった野郎の
クソみてぇな人生に➡
幕を引いてやったんだろ｡
感謝してほしいくらいだぜ｡
He'd thank me if he could.
Ban!
バン！
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)二人とも あれを！
You two, look at that!
あぁ…｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)何か つぶやいているみたい｡
He's mumbling something.
He's still trapped in that illusion,
even after his heart was gouged out.
心臓をえぐられてなお
彼は 幻を見ているのだ｡
Please, forgive your father.
(ﾃﾞｰﾙ)どうか 父を許してくれ｡➡
This happened because I was too weak.
全ては 私の弱さが原因だ｡
お前たちに
何もしてやれなかった｡
I couldn't do anything for you two.
弟を…
ジールを守ってやってくれ｡➡
Please protect your brother, Zeal.
I'm counting on you, Guila.
頼んだぞ ギーラ｡
Farewell, my beloved daughter... my beloved son...
さらばだ｡ 愛しい私の娘➡
私の息子… よ…｡
ぎゃはははっ‼➡
ぎゃははっ！ はははっ！
What's going on?
どうなってやがる!?
心臓は確かに…｡
I'm sure I took his heart.
あっ！ くそっ こいつも魔神か！
Shit, that thing's a demon too?!
(ﾃﾞｨｱﾝﾇ)何？
What?
What is this incredible power?
なんじゃ？
このとてつもない魔力は｡
I'm going to take a look!
様子を見てくる｡
王女様は ここに！
Princess, please stay here!
(心の声)≪メリオダス様…≫
Lord Meliodas...
(ｹｲﾝ)何が起きておるんじゃ｡
What exactly is going on?
≫(ﾃﾞｨｱﾝﾇ)あっ！
(ｹｲﾝ)ん？
Old Man Cain!
ケインのおじいちゃん！
うわっ！ 巨人族か!?
A giantess?!
ん？ なぜ わしのことを？
How do you know me?
あっ エリザベスちゃん！
Elizabeth!
(鎧巨人)ぎゃははっ！
はははっ！ ぎゃはははっ！
Why did a Holy Knight turn into a demon?
(ﾊﾞﾝ)なんで 聖騎士が魔神に!?➡
どうなってる！
What's going on?
思い出した｡ あの顔➡
I remember that face.
That's Dale! He became an apprentice Holy Knight ten years ago!
１０年前 まだ
駆け出しの聖騎士だったデールだ｡
Dale, that doting parent?
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)あの親バカデール!?
おいらたちみたくなって➡
He was always saying he wanted to be strong just like us, so his daughter could be proud of him.
娘の自慢の種になりたいって
よく言っていた…｡➡
How did he become like this?
なぜ こんな姿に｡
来るぞ｡
He's coming.
(鎧巨人)ぎゃははっ！
デール！ 俺を覚えているだろ!?
Dale!
You remember me, right?
Wake up, Dale!
目を覚ませ デール！
何やってんだ バカ！
ドゴン！
What are you doing, idiot?
Ban!
バン！
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)伏せて 団長！➡
Take cover, Captain!
Fight Fire With Fire
｢炸裂する刃雨｣！
Fight fire with fire!
あっ 貫通しない!?
(鎧巨人)ぎゃははっ｡ ははっ！
It didn't penetrate?
だったら…｡
やめろ キング！
How about...
Stop, King!
えっ でも…｡ うわぁ～！
But...
ああっ！
キング！
King!
Dale, knock it off!
デール いいかげんにしろ！
The one who should knock it off...
(ﾊﾞﾝ)いいかげんにするのはよぉ…
てめぇだ！
is you!
あっ
バンが団長を殴った｡ なぜだ？
Ban just hit Captain.
Why?
ゴウセル… 君も少しは戦おうよ｡
Gowther, you need to fight as well.
Please allow me to ponder this for a moment.
少し考えさせてくれないか？
考えるの!?
Ponder?!
If you're not gonna fight, get the hell out of here.
(ﾊﾞﾝ)やる気がねぇなら
ここから うせろ｡➡
That half-assed attitude ain't saving anyone.
中途半端な甘さは誰も救えねぇ｡➡
It'll only get you and your comrades killed.
てめぇと仲間を殺すだけだ｡
Ban...
バン…｡
≪メリオダス様！
Lord Meliodas!
エリザベス！
これを！
Elizabeth!
Take this!
あの剣は…｡
That sword...
(ﾘｽﾞ)((なあ メリオダス))
Hey, Meliodas...
I want you to take this sword.
((お前に
この剣を受け取ってほしいんだ))
Liz didn't want you to keep fighting,
リズさんは戦ってほしかったんじゃ
ありません！
あなたに生きてほしかったから！
but for you to keep on living!
私も同じです｡ 人々のために戦う
あなたのためなら…➡
I feel the same way!
About you, and how you fight for the people!
If that's why you sin,
そのための罪なら…➡
I'll shoulder those sins along with you!
私も一緒に背負います！
Are you really going to let a lady say all that and—
いいのかよ～？
女に あそこまで言わせ… あっ｡
Forgive me, Dale.
許せよ デール｡
ザシュ ザシュ ザシュ ザシュ！
ぐはっ…｡
That's amazing, Captain!
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)すごいじゃない 団長｡
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)さすがだ｡
As expected.
キング 悪かったな｡
King, I'm sorry.
Don't be.
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)
ううん｡ これぐらい大丈夫さ｡
This is nothing.
See, Cap'n, you can do it if you put your mind to it.
やれば 団ちょもできんじゃん｡
ん？
But... is it even possible for a
human to transform into a demon?
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)でも 人間が
魔神に変身するなんてこと➡
ありえるのかな？
う～ん 呪い？
Is it a curse? Or maybe some sort of experiment...
もしくは
なんらかの実験か術か…｡
ポルポルポル！
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)まさか 人為的に➡
Don't tell me, someone's trying to artificially create demons?
魔神を造り出すってこと？
They're using the kingdom's Holy Knights as well.
それも 王国聖騎士を使ってな｡
That's impossible. With the two Great Holy Knights around to keep a watch on...
そんなことが
二人の聖騎士長の目を盗んで➡
できるはず… はっ！
もしかして…｡
Unless..
Yeah.
ああ｡ 聖騎士長本人が
関わっている可能性が高ぇ｡
It's very likely that the Great Holy Knights themselves are involved.
In other words, either Dreyfus, or...
つまり ドレファス あるいは…｡
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)ヘンドリクセン｡
何か分かったのか？
Hendrickson.
Did you figure something out?
Yes.
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)ああ｡ この件に
関わってるとみられる人物は➡
I determined who was probably involved in this incident.
It was most likely the Great Holy Knight Hendrickson.
聖騎士長ヘンドリクセンだ｡
ポル…
Well, I'm pretty hungry, so let's head back.
(ﾊﾞﾝ)さ～て 腹も減ったし戻るか｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)ディアンヌも
心配してるだろうしね｡
I'm sure Diane is worried sick too.
About Captain, sure.
(ﾊﾞﾝ)団ちょのことをな｡
(ｷﾝｸﾞ)むかっ！
Why, you—
(巨人)((ぼおぉ～～！ ぶおっ！))
((ドシュ！))
(巨人)((ぶおっ！ ぶおっ！
ぶおっ！ ぶおっ！))
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)((君は誰だ？
何を興奮している？))
Who are you?
What are you so worked up about?
I see. You don't understand either.
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)
((そうか 君にも分からないのか))
My name is Gowther, the Goat's Sin.
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)
((俺の名は 色欲の罪 ゴウセル))
((この鎧には
魔力の暴走を抑制する➡
This armor has the ability to keep magic from going out of control.
付呪が施されている｡
君に与えよう))
I will give it to you.
Why are you following me?
((なぜ ついてくる？))
Book...
(鎧巨人)((本…))
((君も読むか？))
You wish to read too?
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)
((あっ｡ 分かった 俺が読む))
Understood. I'll read it.
You just stay there and listen.
((君は そこで聞いていてくれ))
I'm going to find more books at the village.
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)((新しい本を探しに
人里へ下りる｡ それにあたり…))
For that...
"My name is Alan."
(ｱﾗﾝ)((僕はアラン｡
趣味は読書です｡ どうでしょう？))
"My hobby is reading books." What do you think?
(鎧巨人)((うっ… ゴウセル…))
Gowther...
((ゴウセルじゃありません｡
アランです))
I'm not Gowther, I'm Alan.
ゴウ… セル…｡
Gowther...
Yes. I'm right here.
はい 僕は ここにいます｡
Th-Thank you...
あ… ありがとう… 友よ…｡
Friend...
Friend?
友…｡ 友達ですか？➡
Like a companion?
I've heard that a friend is
someone who is important to you.
友達とは
大切な人のことだと聞きました｡➡
僕は
君の友達になれたのですか？➡
Was I able to become your friend?
教えてください デール｡
Please tell me, Dale.
I wonder if people normally cry in this situation.
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)人は こんなときに
涙を流すものなのだろうか｡
お前のおかげで
何かが吹っ切れた｡
Thanks to you, I feel like I
was released from something.
行こうぜ｡ ここから先は 死闘だ！
はい！
Let's go.
From now on, we'll fight to the death.
Yes!
kimi no sonzai dake de sekai wa mangekyou mitai da
With just your presence, the world begins to look like a kaleidoscope.
hashiru kimi ni awase keshiki wa irodzuku kara
The scenery fills with color as you run onward.
hora mata kimi no mae de namida wo miseteshimatta
Here I am, showing you my tears again.
nani ga attemo zutto hanaranaide kureta
But no matter what, you always stay by my side.
dareka wo mamorinuku to dareka ni tsumi wo tsukuru
By protecting someone, you create a sin for someone else.
ikiru hodo ai wo shitte kokoro wa tsuyokunaru
Learn of love, and grow stronger the longer you live on.
me no oku ni utsuru kako no kizu wa
But I'll drink down the scars from your past,
watashi ga nomihosu kara
Reflected in the depths of your eyes.
kimi no sonzai dake de sekai wa mangekyou mitai ni
With just your presence, the world begins to look like a kaleidoscope.
kuru kuru mawatte hikari ga sasu
Spinning around and around, shining its light.
kawaru kisetsu to kawaranai waraigoe
The seasons change while our laughing voices remain the same,
kimi wa omoide ni naranai yo
But you'll never be reduced to a memory,
koko ni iru kara
Because you're right here with me.
Here you are, as promised.
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)さあ どうぞ｡ 約束の品よ｡
(ﾍﾙﾌﾞﾗﾑ)う～ん…｡ 確かに
死んだところを確認したな？
You confirmed that it's dead, correct?
(ｽﾚｲﾀﾞｰ)疑り深いじいさんね｡➡
You're quite the skeptical old man.
だったら
その目で 確かめに行けばいいわ｡
Why don't you go confirm it with your own eyes?
(ﾍﾙﾌﾞﾗﾑ)いやいや ご苦労さん｡➡
No, that'll be fine. Good work.
おい ギーラ｡
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)はい｡
Hey, Guila.
Yes?
Can you dispose of this, please?
(ﾍﾙﾌﾞﾗﾑ)これの処分を頼んでいい？
(ｷﾞｰﾗ)はっ？
Yes.
ボゥン！
Okay, good work.
はい よくできました｡
Next Episode's Report
The Goat's Sin, Gowther, of the Seven Deadly Sins has joined the party!
＜七つの大罪 色欲の罪
ゴウセルが 旅の仲間に加わった＞
＜ ちなみに ゴウセルの罪は
色欲の罪である！＞
By the way, Gowther's sin is the sin of lust!
で どの辺が色欲… なわけ？
(ｺﾞｳｾﾙ)そうだな➡
So, how exactly are you lustful?
Let's see...
Here.
この辺とか この辺とか｡➡
And here.
だが いちばんの色欲ポイントは➡
But my most lustful point is...
ここだろう｡
Right here!
Next time, on the Seven
Deadly Sins: "Incited Legends."
＜次回 『七つの大罪』
｢駆り立てられる伝説たち｣＞
よ～し！ じゃあ
俺も いっちょ 色欲ってみるぜ｡
All right!
I'll show you a lustful point too, then!
Episode 16
Incited Legends
過激派イスラム国とされるグルー
プによる
日本人人質事件は新たな局面を迎
えた｡
湯川遥菜さんの遺体とされる
新たに公開された画像について､